<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>STA 112FS: Data Science on STA 112FS</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in STA 112FS: Data Science on STA 112FS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Note: Due dates of bigger assignments and exams will not move, however the timeline of topics might be updated throughout the semester.  Date Lesson Reading Assignment Slides Exam   PART 1: Visualizing data       Tue, Aug 29 Welcome to Data Science       Thur, Aug 31 Introduction to R/RStudio &amp;#43; git/GitHub       Tue, Sept 5 Fundamentals of data &amp;amp; data visualization       Thur, Sept 7 Visualizing spatial data, and more       Tue, Sept 12 Data Visualization and Exploration, Pt 1       Thur, Sept 14 Data Visualization and Exploration, Pt 2        Resolving merge conflicts       Tue, Sept 19 Confounding variables and Simpson&amp;#39;s paradox       Thur, Sept 21 Case studies: SAT scores and smoking       PART 2: Wrangling data       Tue, Sept 26 Tidy data &amp;#43; data wrangling       Thur, Sept 28 Types of variables       Tue, Oct 3 Recoding variables and transformations       PART 3: Making rigorous conclusions       Thur, Oct 5 The language of models       Tue, Oct 10 No class: Fall break       Thur, Oct 12 Formalizing linear models       Tue, Oct 17 Multiple linear regression       Thur, Oct 19 Model selection        Case study: Model selection for Paris Paintings       Tue, Oct 24 Prediction and model validation       Thur, Oct 26 Estimation via bootstrapping       Tue, Oct 31 Hypothesis testing via simulation methods       Thur, Nov 2 Inference for numerical data       Tue, Nov 7 Inference for categorical data       Thur, Nov 9 Central Limit Theorem       Tue, Nov 14 Case study: Building models messy data       PART 4 Looking forward       Thur, Nov 16 Web scraping       Tue, Nov 21 Interactive visualizations with Shiny, Pt 2       Thur, Nov 23 No class: Thanksgiving       Tue, Nov 28 Interactive visualizations with Shiny, Pt 1       Thur, Nov 30 Bayesian inference, Pt 1       Tue, Dec 5 Bayesian inference, Pt 2       Thur, Dec 7 Final project presentations       </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Policies</title>
      <link>/policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/policies/</guid>
      <description>Class: Class time is designed to be as interactive as possible. My role as instructor is to introduce you new tools and techniques, but it is up to you to take them and make use of them. Programming is a skill that is best learned by doing, so as much as possible you will be working on a variety of tasks and activities throughout each class.
Grading: Your final grade will be comprised of the following:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>R/RStudio     GitHub     Slack    R is the statistical programming language we will learn in this class. We will interface with R using RStudio, a fully feautred IDE. Go to https://vm-manage.oit.duke.edu/ to access RStudio and log in with your Net ID.    GitHub is a web-based version control repository and Internet hosting service. We will be using GitHub in this course as a collaboration platform and a course management system (i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>